<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Toronto Nepali Film Festival</title>
    <link>http://tnff.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Toronto Nepali Film Festival</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:43:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tnff.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kalo Pothi</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/kalo-pothi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:43:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/kalo-pothi/</guid>
      <description>Trailer
Nepal | 2015 | Fiction | 90 mins | Khash with English subtitles
Director: Min Bahadur Bham, email: nabinbham12@gmail.com
Producers: Anna Katchko, Tsering Rhitar Sherpa, Debaki Rai, Catherine Dussart, Min Bahadur Bham and Anup Thapa
Synopsis: Year 2001, a temporary ceasefire brings much-needed break to a small war-torn village in Northern Nepal, bringing much joy among the residents. Prakash and Kiran, two young close friends, are also starting to feel the change in the air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invincible Swayambhu</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/invincible-swayambhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:41:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/invincible-swayambhu/</guid>
      <description>Nepal | 2017 | Documentary | 7 mins | Nepali with English subtitles
Director: Baburam Raut, email: rautronish@gmail.com
Producers: World Bank Nepal and Onion Films Nepal
Synopsis: In this documentary, a priest and heritage expert discusses the vulnerable situation and future of the Swayambhu Temple after being impacted by the earthquake in 2015.
Previous Screenings and Awards: Selected in the Fifth International Festival of Short Films on Culture &amp;amp; Tourism (IFFC-V)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Life in Monochrome</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/finding-life-in-monochrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:39:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/finding-life-in-monochrome/</guid>
      <description>Darjeeling | 2017 | Documentary | 10 mins | Nepali and Hindi with English subtitles
Director: Wangyal Sherpa, email: iamwangyal@gmail.com
Producers: National Child Labour Project (NCLP), Labour Department, Darjeeling
Synopsis: This documentary deals with the stories of children living in Edith Wilkins (NGO), Darjeeling, who have suffered from various forms of child abuse.
Director&amp;rsquo;s Bio:
Wangyal Sherpa is a Mass Communication and Journalism graduate from Darjeeling District of West Bengal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jhajalko</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/jhajalko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:38:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/jhajalko/</guid>
      <description>Darjeeling | 2017 | Fiction | 18 mins | Nepali with English subtitles
Director: Wangyal Sherpa, email: iamwangyal@gmail.com
Producers: Wangyal Sherpa and Anup Aadin Das
Synopsis: This fictions follows series of memories of Sarita after she receives the tragic news of her husband’s death. This film shows Sarita’s struggles as she has to raise her son on her own.
Director&amp;rsquo;s Bio:
Wangyal Sherpa is a Mass Communication and Journalism graduate from Darjeeling District of West Bengal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nirvana</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/nirvana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:36:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/nirvana/</guid>
      <description>United States | 2017 | Short | 3 mins | No dialogues
Director: Anup Giri, email: anupgiriofficial@gmail.com
Producer: Kelly Pvt. Ltd
Synopsis: This short explores the topic of Nirvana, finding inner peace, which equals to the ultimate form of happiness. This short depicts the message of search for happiness within you and not in materialist objects.
Director&amp;rsquo;s Bio:
Anup Giri is the director, editor and the writer of this movie Nirvana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jaalgedi</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/jaalgedi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:33:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/jaalgedi/</guid>
      <description>Trailer
Nepal | 2017 | Short |15 mins | Nepali with English subtitles
Director: Rajesh Prasad Khatri; email: nabinbham12@gmail.com
Producer: Min Bahadur Bham
Synopsis: Jaalgedi takes her family&amp;rsquo;s animals, like any other day, to pastures outside her remote village. However, the arrival of a white tourist sends shockwaves among the children of the village who have never seen a foreigner in their lives before. Like all her friends, the inquisitive little girl gets distracted from her responsibilities of a while - following the strange white man around the village - only to find a catastrophe has befallen because of her innocent curiosities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gya</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/gya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:29:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/gya/</guid>
      <description>Nepal | 2017 | Short | 5 mins | Nepali with English subtitles
Director: Pratish Shrestha, email: pratish.shrestha2018@gmail.com
Producer: Pratish Shrestha
Synopsis: This film depicts the journey of a modern man from chaos to meditative state and his search for meaning of his existence.
Previous Screenings and Awards: Visionaria Santa Maria della Scala 2017- Italy
Mitreo Film Festival 2017
U Special International Campus Film Festival 2017
Director&amp;rsquo;s Bio:
Pratish Shrestha is a film student from Nepal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ananta Yatra</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/ananta-yatra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:24:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/ananta-yatra/</guid>
      <description>Nepal | 2016 | Short | 15 mins | Nepali with English Subtitles
Director: Sunil Pandey, email: sunil204947@gmail.com
Producer: Sunil Pandey
Synopsis: This film is a chronicle about the journey of an elderly woman who suddenly passes away in 2015 due to the Nepal earthquake. The film depicts an emotional eulogy to the director’s beloved grandmother.
Director&amp;rsquo;s Bio:
Sunil Pandey graduated from Oscar Int. College in Nepal. He specialized in the field of Direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lachhamaniya</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/lachhamaniya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:21:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/lachhamaniya/</guid>
      <description>Nepal | 2017 | Short | 16 mins | Aawadhi with English subtitles
Director: Bikas Neupane, email: hamrobox@gmail.com
Producer: Govinda Prasad Khanal
Synopsis This short depicts the practice of arranged marriage in Nepal. It shows the story of a vivacious young woman who is about to get married with a man that she has never met.
Previous Screenings and Awards: 15th Kathmandu International Mountain Film Festival (Dec 2017)
5th Ekadeshma International Short film Festival (Nov 2017) - Audience Choice Award</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maila Dai</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/maila-dai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:15:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/maila-dai/</guid>
      <description>Nepal | 2017 | Documentary | 6 mins | Nepali with English subtitles
Director: Rajeela Shrestha, email: rajeelashrestha@gmail.com
Producer: Onion Films
Synopsis: Maila Dai is a documentary about Maila Lama, who is considered a hero. This documentary is about the experience, struggle and contribution of Maila Lama who not only recovered his business but also helped rebuild the village of Thangpalkot, Sindhupalchowk after the massive earthquake that hit Nepal in April 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eldest Son</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/the-eldest-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:05:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/the-eldest-son/</guid>
      <description>Nepal | 2017 | Documentary | 30 mins | Nepali with English subtitles
Director: Amy Benson, email: benson@nonfictionmedia.com
Producer: Scott Squire
Synopsis: The Eldest Son is a short documentary about Kumar Darnal, a young Nepali man who leaves his wife and two small children to become a migrant laborer in Malaysia with the dream of ending his family’s cycle of poverty. Will the risk pay off? The Eldest Son asks what is the emotional cost of migrant labor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curious Case of Bhim Thapa</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/curious-case-of-bhim-thapa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:01:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/curious-case-of-bhim-thapa/</guid>
      <description>Nepal | 2015 | Documentary | 14 mins | Nepali with English subtitles
Director: Bhakta Chand, email: bhaktachand@gmail.com
Producers: Bhakta Chand and Gopal Shivakoti
Synopsis: This documentary centers on a man, a myth and his legacy and works both as a biopic and as a timelessly relevant piece of social commentary. Mr. Bhim Thapa has dedicated his life on the idea that people need to be awakened to bring changes in their lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Tiffany</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/pink-tiffany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 20:56:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/pink-tiffany/</guid>
      <description>Trailer
Nepal | 2017 | Documentary | 44 mins | Nepali with English subtitles
Director: Sophie Dia Pegru, email: sophie.pegrum@gmail.com
Producer: Miranda Morton Yap (Shakti Pictures)
Synopsis: While Nepal may be a beacon of progress, legally recognizing an “other” gender, this film is breaking the silence on the daily struggle to gain not only social legitimacy, but also family acceptance, perhaps the largest hurdle for all of our personal journeys and dreams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TNFF 2018 Schedule</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/tnff-2018-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 15:30:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/tnff-2018/tnff-2018-schedule/</guid>
      <description>Saturday May 19th, 2018 Session A (1:30 PM - 3:30 PM) 1:45 Pink Tiffany (44 mins) by Sophie Dia Pegrum
2:30 The Curious Case of Mr. Bhim Thapa (14 mins) by Bhakta Chand
2:45 The Eldest Son (30 mins) by Amy Benson
3:15 Maila Dai - A Man Who Rebuilt a Village (6 mins) by Rajeela Shrestha
Session B (4:00 PM - 5:45 PM) 4:30 Lachhamaniya (16 mins) by Bikas Neupane</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submissions for TNFF 2018 are open</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/news/call-for-submissions-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 15:05:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/news/call-for-submissions-2018/</guid>
      <description>For information in Nepal please contact:
Sangam Pulami Magar
pulamisangam@gmail.com
For information in Canada or outside of Nepal please contact:
Marygold Bhandari
executivedirector@tnff.ca
Entries are now being accepted for the 9th Annual Toronto Nepali Film Festival to be held on May 19th, 2018.
Films will be selected based on merit and the content of the films. The jury will consider relevant Nepali narratives, methods of storytelling, new genres in the context of Nepali filmmaking, technical finesse, and other attributes of filmmaking in the selection process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://tnff.ca/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tnff.ca/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to send just a message for any questions you have. We&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your feedback!
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>